CLINTON CECIL

608-469-3183 clinton.cecil@gmail.com

4313 Severson Dr. Madison, WI 53718

Profile

Experienced lead programmer with a record of delivering cost-effective and user-friendly solutions. Knowledgable in all phases of software development. Strong background in mathematics, algorithms, database design and data structures.

Skills

Experience working with multiple object-oriented programming languages (Ruby on Rails, Javascript, Python and Groovy / Grails), multiple database systems (Postgres, NoSQL, MySQL, Oracle, Redis and DynamoDB). Adept at developing RESTful APIs. Knowledgable with commercial and open-source tools.

Experience

Senior Software Engineer, Primex: Lake Geneva, WI — 2014-Present
Developed and supported the APIs for an application consisting of 10 main services
and 33 supporting services across more than 300 EC2 instances. Used AWS
Lambda, DynamoDB, Redis, MySQL, Kinesis, Ruby on Rails, AngularJS, Python.
Migration to our system supported 4 times as many devices at 60% of the original
cost. Supported 140,000 devices including 110,000 weather devices. Supported 18
billion updates a month.

Senior Programmer Analyst, CTAC: Fairfax, VA — 2011-2014

Led migration from subversion to git company wide, including shell scripting to retain all history. Developed in Ruby on Rails for new features and bug fixes across multiple projects used internally by the federal government. Supported the highest trafficked site hosted by the GSA using java. Developed Groovy/Grails application that supported multiple agencies and synchronized data across them. Participated in requirements gathering and support meetings, as well as proposals.

Software Developer, Epic Systems: Verona, WI - 2010-2011 Contributed to large scale systems used in medium to large medical groups and research facilities with a focus on ambulatory services. Trained hospital staff in the use of software on site. Developed ophthalmology components for eye-care professionals.

Education

Frostburg State University: Frostburg, MD-M.S. Computer Science, 2010 Frostburg State University: Frostburg, MD-B.S. Mathematics, Minor in Computer Science, 2008

CLINTON CECIL

608-469-3183 clinton.cecil@gmail.com

4313 Severson Dr. Madison, WI 53718

References

Brian Balboni - Primex - CTO bbalboni@primexinc.com (262) 249-3062 965 Wells St Lake Geneva, WI 53147

Kevin Runde - Primex - Chief Architect rundeks@gmail.com (email to schedule call)

Aaron Stowell - CTAC - CTO astowell@ctacorp.com (703) 289-3809 3120 Fairview Park Dr Falls Church, VA 22042

Juan Alvarado - CTAC - Project Lead jalvarado@ctacorp.com (410) 726-8183 11232 W Tammy Drive Bishopville, MD 21813